My friend Jerry brought me some sausages made of artificial pork from US
...and two packs of "beef"
What's about the price of the "beef"?
This one costs around 70 yuan
Is it 500 grams for the 70 yuan pack?
it's 450 grams
ok, 450 grams
About 900g, yet to reach 1 kilo
I think this is sold here double of the price than in the states
And it's still two times more expensive than fresh beef...
Not sure about how it will taste like after being cooked
Got to decide if it's worth buying after we try it
Could this taste better than real meat?
What do you think?
The color of it resembles that of the cooked beef
Fresh beef has bright red
This appears to have the color of dull-red
It's dimmer
As for the sausage
Looks not bad
There might be some food additives
It has the unique pork flavor to it
Alright, let's cook
I plan to cook the sausages with chili and garlic sprouts
The dish is called "Stir-fry Sausage"
The artificial beef can braise with tofu
To make "Mapo Tofu"
For the pork I'll mince it and cut up some cowpea for a stir-fry
Can you eat spicy food?
I can
Too what degree?
Extra spicy
We are going to use very spicy chili though
Is this chili pepper? It's not.
We have a very spicy kind of chili here, I'm afraid that you cannot bear it
It's a ok to try it
Fine, next up, cooking
Cut this open
It includes various kinds of oil such as coconut oil
Plenty of coconut oil
Those are all vegetable oils, right?
Ye
It doesn't matter--you can eat it raw
Edible?
Edible!
What does it taste like?
Real beef ain't that tender
Positive
This actually tastes like hard bean curd
Somewhat similar to wheat gluten
It's made from lots of beans
beans?
That's why
For 70 yuan
I'm not likely to spend 70 yuan on barely 500 grams of artificial meat
Why
Expensive!
And it doesn't get all the flavors unique to real beef
Ok
It's all too soon to judge
White colored
This is coconut
coconut?
Why do they use this? Cuz there are fat content in the real meat
So some portions should be white
The rest is protein
They use coconut to mimic the taste and the look of meat
It won't look realistic without coconuts
Real pork looks quite different from beef
ok
Its color and muscle fiber do not look alike at all
Also the flavor
It will not be the same
We don't want to eat all of it raw, let's start cutting them
It feels too soft when cutting through
but then you are doing a good job
That's because I do cooking for a living
Traveling around the world with one Kitchen Knife
Aren't the vegetables in the states larger?
Vegetables in the states cost much more than here
Because the consumers have little access to freshly picked vegetables
A chunky tofu
Gonna cook ""Mapo Tofu" with that "beef" for lunch
Sounds good
That's a lot of tofu
No worry, we got a bunch of people around
Do US chief cuts in a similar why?
They use some kind of machine to do the job for them
They basically utilize the machines to cook dishes like this
Some chiefs with good knife skills can cut while blindfolded #(sounds exactly like a senior chinese chief...)
Are you able to start the fire? Jerry
One sec.
Let me take a look
Ok, this is insufficient
Not enough firewood, a bit more
ok
Put more or the fire's gonna extinguish again
Let's do the "Stir-fry Pork" first
You cook the pork with chili and garlic sprouts
Let's start with chili pepepr
And add this in
The sound of it when cooking differs quite a lot from real beef
It finished?
All good
Do you know that Mapo Tofu is my favorite dish
for real?
This will have some pressure on you
XD
And the meat as well
Add soe Sichuan Pepper corn
You can put more
Gonna add more later
Ok
This dish will be hot as hell
Add the Tofu into the wok
Ready to serve
You sure that you can bear the numbness?
Well I love it
Alright, then we can add a bit more
Sprinkle this to enhance the fragrance
The restaurant way to prepare the mince port is to marinate the meat in advance
After which the chief will give it a stir fry, so the dish is halfway done
And no more seasoning needed
You don't have to marinate it if the cooking is done in the house
Season it in the wok
Since this meat seems to be already lightly seasoned
We don't have to add too much seasoning
fry this first in a similar way
Always cook auxiliary ingredients first
Stir fry to a point that it's barely cooked, then add this in
This gets all scattered around unlike the previous one
Unlike that beef
Add some soy sauce and it will be good
This is pork
right, this is pork
You brought it from US?
Ye
How do you like the US pork?
Bot bad
You can eat that one which is the numbest
This is already slightly numb I guess?
Bear witness with me, I take the challenge
Too numb
He likes it
Uncle try this one
It's American beef
How does it compare to Chinese beef
Crispy
Right
Chinese beef are soft and chewy
Uncle let me tell you the truth, the meat is artificial
Not authentic beef, it's kinda faked
Many different types of beans and proteins from vegetables
And there is also salt
A friction of oil
This is what it looks like when putting together
This barely weighs 500 grams , however it's sold at the price of 70 yuan
Wow, quite expensive
Which one tastes better to you? The Chinese ones or this one?
The Chinese beef tastes more chewy
This kind of beef tastes loose
Another difference is the crispiness which normal beef doesn't have
Which one will you choose if you want to get some beef
I'll definitely go with the real beef
What if they are sold at the same price point
I'll buy the real beef even if the prices are the same
Gonna eat the real things
Some people prefer this, it is sold out at a numbers of supermarket
They had only limited production power
And they have gone public
Public company? Not saleable in China!
Unfortunately
The factory will be shut down selling vegetarian mean in China
About why it's selling well in your place, I think
I'll take a guess
It might be because that artificial meant represents a low-risk alternative?
Because it's likely more sanitized
Or it could be specially made for vegetarians in your country
...as vegetarians are able to eat this kind of meat made from plants
For the most part, it is Vegetarians or people that are into the vegetarianism culture that are buying this
If you are consuming artificial meant, many people would consider you as a "man of culture", or someone that is on another level
They think that the world will be a better place if people turn to artificial meat
This is the topic of conversation that can make your popular among your friends
well, it does not seem to work here
But huge thanks to Jerry my man
Who brought this all the way from America to let us have a change to taste it
Well this is just some average food that we have
It's not some delicious ingredient to begin with
But you definitely make it taste fantastic with your culinary skills
There was never ever a person that can turn artificial meat into a delicacy as you did
You are the first one on the earth to accomplish that